肯定在哪 要继续找吗
Gotta be somewhere. You wanna keep goin'?
我是Smith警员 女士
Officer Smith, ma'am.
我们再找一个昨晚攻击一名女子的男人
We're looking for a man  went after a woman last night
就在你后面的Esplanda公寓
at Esplanda Apartments  aruound right behind you.
- 有听到什么反常的声音吗 - 不好意思 没有
- Heard anything unusual? - No, sorry.
天啊 太可怕了 那女的还好吧
Oh my God, that's terrible. Is the woman all right?
- 那名女子 她还好吧 - 嗯 还好
- The woman, is she all right? - Yeah, she good.
不好意思 我哥哥 Omar Little 昨晚来的
Excuse me. My brother, Omar Little,  came here last night.
他从那该死的窗口摔了下来
He fell out the damn window.
- 没这个名字 - 他可能嗑高了
- We don't have anyone by that name. - He was kinda high.
搞错了名字 人很黑 脸上有道疤
Probably messed up his name. Real dark, got himself a scar.
腿伤得很严重
Legs should be busted up real bad.
昨晚我们没接收过那样伤情的病人
No one with that type of injury came in last night.
毛都没有
Not a goddamn thing.
我们翻遍了附近三个街区的 每间空屋 每个垃圾桶
Been in every trash can,dumpster,  vacant for three blocks 'round.
- 一无所获 - 我们甚至连下水道都找过了
- Nothin'. - We even checked down the sewers.
- Marlo要见面 - 你要我们怎么做
- Marlo wanna meet. - So what you want us to do?
哪间
Which one?
- 怎么可能 - 是不可能
- Don't seem possible. - It don't.
跟蜘蛛侠一样犀利啊
That some Spiderman shit there.
我们错失了大好良机
We missed our shot.
现在轮到他对付我们了
Now he gonna be at us.
* When you walk through the garden *
火线重案组 第五季 第6集
the wire s05 ep06
* you gotta watch your back *
* well I beg your pardon *
* walk the straight and narrow track *
* if you walk with Jesus *
* he's gonna save your soul *
* you gotta keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
* he's got the fire and the fury *
* at his command *
* well you don't have to worry *
* if you hold on to Jesus hand *
* we'll all be safe from Satan *
* when the thunder rolls *
* just gotta help me keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
www.1000fr.net presents
你要有不满 我完全理解 -- Freamom
平时我的幕僚都不让我拿锋利的东西
Usually, my staff tries to keep  sharp objects out of my hands.
Charles Center：巴尔的摩市中心的重建计划
众所周知 先是Charles Center和Tommy d'Alesandro
You know, it all started with  Charles Center and Tommy d'Alesandro
接着是William Donald Schaefer 和港区
and it continued with  William Donald Schaefer and Harborplace.
那之后是Schmoke和O'Malley市长的 内港东部地区
And following that, there were mayors Schmoke and O'Malley with Inner Harbor East.
现在轮到我的政府
Well, today it is my  administration's turn to
在Patapsco中部烙下我们的烙印
lay claim to the middle  branch of the Patapsco
这里很快会成为新的西港
and what will soon become known as New Westport,
为我们伟大的城市又一个滨水区迎来复兴
revitalizing another waterfront  area of our great city.
谢谢
Thank you.
跟Locust南湾头说再见吧
Say goodbye to Locust Point South.
- 去你的 Krawczyk - 就是 去你的
- Fuck you, Krawczyk. - Yeah, fuck you
混蛋爱尔兰佬
greedhead motherfucker.
去你妈的 拆了巴尔的摩的港口
Fuck you for tearing down the port of Baltimore
卖给华盛顿的雅皮混蛋
and selling it to some yuppie assholes from Washington.
- 拜托 伙计 - 狗屎
- C'mon, buddy. - This is bullshit.
- 谁啊 - 小人物 市长先生 他屁都不算
- Who the hell's that?  - That's nobody, Mr. Mayor. It's nobody at all.
- 高兴了? 贱人 - 是 我很满意
- You happy now, bitch? - I am content, yes.
- 你给记者打电话了? - 其实没有
- You called the reporter? - No, actually.
那混球自己意淫呢
That asshole's making up his own shit.
Brass中午要开个新闻发布会
Brass called a press conference for this afternoon.
他们会给我大笔钱查案 你见了都晕
They'll be shoveling so much money at my bullshit it'll make your head spin.
- 拿那么多档案干嘛 - 空屋案
- What's with all the casework? - Bodies from the vacants.
- 还有些都还没化验 - 悲剧...
- Some still missing lab work. - Pathetic...
有些还进展不错
And some of them have been worked pretty good.
知道吗 Jimmy?
You know what, Jimmy?
我得从头开始 把他们每一个都查过
I'm gonna go back to the beginning and work every one of them again.
从头开始
Back to square one.
知道为什么吗 因为我是查凶杀案的警察
You know why? Because I'm a murder police.
我抓凶手
I work murders.
我不弄虚作假 不来阴的
I don't fuck with no make-believe,  I don't jerk shit around.
我抓凶手 查案子
I catch a murder and I work it.
尽我的职责
Working this shit like I'm supposed to.
你有需要的话尽管开口 行吗
Well, let me know if you need anything, all right?
车啊 加班啊 化验啊... 尽管开口
Cars, some OT, some lab work... Anything you need.
因为再有三四个小时我的案子就有资金了
Because in three or four hours the money's gonna flow on my case.
要多少给多少 Bunk 我估计拿到的Lester花也花不完
Whatever you need, I'm probably gonna  have more of it than even Lester could use.
跟一个连环杀手那么接近 一定很诡异
To be that close to a serial killer. It must be weird.
有点吧
Kinda. Yeah.
- 精彩的报道 Scott - 是啊 故事本身就很吸引人
- Wonderful story, Scott. - Yeah, well, it kinda wrote itself.
很幸运那家伙找我...
It's lucky to have the guy  call me like he did...
那都是走访的功劳 可不只是幸运
It comes from pounding the pavement, right? That's more than luck.
你是到了新闻会找上你的地方
That's putting yourself in the place  where the story comes to you.
- 明天有什么想法 - 明天?
- What do you have for tomorrow? - for tomorrow?
这新闻我们可不能就炒个一两天
This is not the kind of thing we let go of after a day or two.
我想着跟流浪汉混上一晚
I was thinking that if I spent a night with the homeless, you know.
做他们做的事 见他们所见 之类的
Did what they did. Saw what they saw. that kinda thing.
我是说如果通宵的话 明天可交不了
i mean If it's an overnight thing,  I couldn't get it for tomorrow,
- 但后天就没问题了... - 太好了
- but the next day, sure... - That's great.
这会是个完美的跟踪报道 我去跟Gus说
That could be the perfect follow. I'll speak to Gus.
还有 Scott 我们一直接到些 广播公司和有线电视的电话
Also, Scott. We've been taking calls from  some of the networks and cable outlets.
- 他们想让你上镜头 - 我? 上电视?
- They're looking for you to go on-camera. - Me? On television?
我会避开本地的节目 但如果你愿负责地上些全国性的...
I'd avoid locals, but if you can do the national stuff responsibly...
当然可以
Sure, yeah.
我是说 我有点不太能接受
I mean,I'm just not all that  comfortable having myself
处在事件的中心
in the center of the story like this.
当然 但总有负责的处置办法
Of course not. But there is a way of handling this responsibly.
记住你是本报的形象大使
Just remember you're an ambassador for the paper.
明星时段
Star time.
是啊 又怎么样
How about that?
无家可归?
Homelessness?
我们的报道可以折射出 狄更斯笔下的流浪汉生活
Our coverage should reflect the Dickensian aspect of the homeless.
那些人性元素
The human element.
Scott牵头 在街上过一晚
Scott will lead it off, spending a night on the streets
从这个视角写
and writing from that perspective.
Scott? 他要做你的教育题材
scott?He's the lead on your education project.
我认为我们得把他放回...
i think We need to get him back on the...
我不认为学校的题材有流浪汉
I don't see the school project  as yielding the same kind of impact
的情况影响大
as our attention to homelessness can.
凶手 给记者的电话
These murders, the phone call to our reporter.
大有文章可做 不是吗
It really opens up the issue.dont you think?
- 是 但... - 从现在开始到年底
- Yeah, but... - From now till the end of the year,
我们不仅要报道那些凶手
let's focus not only on covering the murders,
还要关注无家可归者这个人群的状况
but on the nature of homelessness itself.
狄更斯笔下的世界 是啊
The Dickensian aspect of it. Yeah.
我到一个点了 Sydnor警探
I've reached a point, Detective Sydnor,
我再没有时间和耐性
where I no longer have the time or patience left
让自己限制在系统的条条框框里了
to address myself to the needs of  the system within which we work.
- 我累了 - 你要退休?
- I'm tired. - You're gonna quit?
还没有 还没到时候
Not yet. Not just yet.
那你什么意思
So what are you talking about?
他们这次让我们放弃查Marlo
When they took us off Marlo this last time,
说他们没钱进行进一步调查
when they said they couldn't pay for further investigation,
我认为这个决定是不合法的
I regarded that decision as illegitimate.
- 不合法? - 因此...
- Illegitimate? - And so...
我要礼尚往来
I'm responding in kind.
我要用非常规手段调查Marlo Stanfield
I'm going to press a caseagainst Marlo  Stanfield without regard to the usual rules.
我要非法窃听Marlo Stanfield的手机
I'm running an illegal wiretap on Marlo Stanfield's cellphone.
- 靠 Lester? - 如果你有意见
- Fuck. Lester? - If you have a problem with this,
我完全理解
I understand completely
并且我强烈要求你离我越远越好
and I urge you to get as far  fucking away from me as you can.
记得这个吗
You remember this one here?
我出于对傻小子Prez的尊重 没找这孩子麻烦
I backed away from jackin' the boy up outta respect for that goofy motherfucker Prez.
想知道这小伙一年后会告诉我什么...
Wonder what the young man might tell me a year later, though...
什么玩意
What the fuck is this?
Vernon搜查了他手上某受害人的五金店
Vernon here did a search warranton  his dead guy's appliance store
从桌子抽屉里翻出来的
pulled all of that out of the desk drawer.
- 大陪审团的文件? - 副本 密封的起诉状...
- Grand jury shit? - Transcripts, sealed indictments...
- 死者是谁 - 东区叫Joe Stewart的毒贩
- Who's your murder? - Eastside dealer by the name of Joe Stewart.
昨晚后脑挨了一枪
Caught one in the back of his head the other night.
终于有人动Prop Joe了
Somebody finally touched Prop Joe.
记得去年缉毒科要指控Charlie Burman吗
You remember when Narcotics indicted Charlie Burman last year?
那混球在逮捕前几条跑路了 依然在逃
Motherfucker ran a couple days before the raids, still on the wing.
密封的起诉状都在这儿呢 所有的
The sealed indictments are all in there. Every one of 'em.
法院里我们最不信任的是谁
Who don't we trust at the courthouse?
- 他们在炸薯条上放芝士? - 对啊 还放辣椒呢
- They put cheese on them fries? - They can. Chili too.
- 好吧 - 要喝的吗
- All right, then. - You want a drink with that?
- 草莓柠檬水 - 好的 我去买
- Strawberry lemonade. - All right, I'm on it.
他们又用手机了 过了一年多之后?
They're back on cellphones. After more than a year?
- 是啊 - 告诉我他们是在说暗语 Lester
- That they are. - Tell me they're talking in code, Lester.
我可不想因为窃听Marlo的午餐订单进监狱
I wanna go to jail for snatchin'  something better than Marlo's lunch order.
听不出什么暗语 好几个电话了
There's no code that I can tell. Half dozen calls.
都是日常对话  不提及毒品 没数字 时间...
All routine. No drug talk,  no numbers, no times...
只说他们看见的东西
Nothing but what they seem.
那他们就不是用电话谈生意
So he ain't doing  business with the phone then.
关了吧 我们出去吧
Take this mess down. Let's get outta here.
我还听到5个电话 持续时间30到40秒
I also have five calls, 30 to 40 seconds' duration,
每个都是响第一声就接
each one picked up on the first ring
两边都不说话
each one with nothing  whatsoever said between parties.
懂吗 他们说的都是屁话
You see? When they talk, it's bullshit.
但有些电话是大家都不出声的
But there are calls  where no one says a thing.
30秒 不说话
Thirty seconds, without conversation.
他...
Is he...
我们谈过了 他知道风险
We talked it through, he knows the risks.
算我一个 如果能立得了案 我当仁不让
I'm in. If it makes the fucking case, I'm in all the way.
现在怎么样 他们有说坏事吗
So, what's up now?  They talking dirt?
- 没有 - Lester 我操
- No. - Lester. Fuck.
Marlo不会在电话里谈坏事的 但有些猫腻
Marlo's not gonna talk dirt on the phone, but there's something to this.
我只是还没想明白
I just haven't figured it out.
我们需要些人手
We could use some more manpower
需要些人监视这些家伙
we need a couple of surveillance  teams to get on  these guys
搞清楚他们是怎么用手机的
to see how they using the phones.
你今天看报纸了吗
You see the newspaper today?
这样的头版头条 老大们会给流浪汉谋杀案投钱的
Headline like that, the bosses are gonna  start throwing money at the homeless murders.
到时候我会拨几个人给你
When they do, I'll peel off a couple  detectives, throw them your way.
流浪汉谋杀案? 那案子怎么会搅和进来的
The homeless murders? How does that case tangle in with this?
一言难尽
Hard to explain.
记得党代会那些家伙两年前怎么跟我说的吗
Remember what the DNC  folks told me two years ago?
怎么入主州政府
How to take the statehouse?
在市中心建个刻着你名字的玩意
Build something downtown and stick your name on it,
降低犯罪率 远离学校
get the crime to go down, and stay away from schools.
- 维持我的年轻美好形象 - 这四个里起码有个做得不错
- And keep my boyish good looks. - One out of four ain't bad.
老天
Jesus.
一定要安排在跟新西港同一天吗
Did we have to schedule this  the same day as New Westport?
我的好消息连地方新闻首页都进不了了
My good news isn't even going to  make the front of the local section.
剪彩两周前就安排好了
The ribbon-cutting was  scheduled two weeks ago.
没人能聊到这流浪汉的谋杀案
the homeless thing coming No one saw .
首先 我很讶异会在此看到这么多媒体
First of all, I'm surprised to see so much media here.
今天早些时候有个宣布我们的城市
A press event held earlier today to announce the revitalization
复兴计划的新闻发布会 参加率没那么高
of yet another part of our city was not so well attended.
显然媒体的注意力往往集中在 巴尔的摩的负面新闻上
It would appear that media attention is  always focusing on the negatives in Baltimore
但我们取得进步时你们却不闻不问
but you aren't around when we're making real progress.
不过 我还是很高兴你们能到来
Still, I'm glad to see so many of you here.
你们中有些代表的不仅是本地的媒体
Some of you representing not just our local media,
还代表全国对这一问题的关注
but national attention to this problem.
感谢你们对我们最弱势的群体的关心
Thank you for caring enough about our most vulnerable citizens
来参与报道这个惨剧
to address yourselves to this tragedy.
我们的流浪汉人口 被社会遗忘的人
Our homeless citizens, those who have  fallen through the cracks of our society,
没人注意关心他们
those who command the least  of our attentions and efforts,
也不受政客的喜爱
they seemingly have little to  endear themselves to politicians.
他们大多不会投票 对竞选可有可无
They don't vote, by and large. They don't contribute to campaigns.
对城市税基贡献甚微
They offer little to a city's tax base,
在其他方面也难以让政府察觉他们的存在
and to the extent that our government is made aware of their existence,
政府只会试图缓解他们的存在带来的伤痛
it responds by trying to mitigate the damage done by their presence.
我们这儿建个食品站 那儿建个庇护所
We open a food bank here, a shelter there.
我们试图把他们赶出市区
We try to move them away from downtown,
让他们远离社区 学校 远离我们的家
away from our communal areas, away from our schools, away from our homes.
如果以我们的社会对待这些 流离街头的人的方式来评判这个社会
If you were to judge our society by the manner in which we treat those lost on our streets,
我们该感到羞愧
we would have cause to be shamed.
愿上帝宽恕 我是个政客
Well, I am, God forgive me, a politician.
但我因相信能有不一样的治理方式而竞选公职
But I ran for public office because I believe that there is a different way of governing.
我相信最终评判我们的标准
And I believe that in the end  we will be judge not by the efforts
不是我们给予那些给我们投票 为竞选付出的人
we make on behalf of those who vote for us, who contribute to our campaigns,
又或者是得到纳税人多少帮助
or those who provide for our tax base.
我相信我们做得好坏取决于 我们能提供给弱势人群什么
I believe that we will be judged by what we provide to the weakest and most vulnerable.
这是个考验 一个对我的考验
That is the test. That is my test.
有人在杀害这城市的流浪汉
Somebody is killing homeless men in this city.
他们在夺取那些无力保护自己的人的生命
there Taking the lives of fellow citizens who do not have the means or the strength
必须阻止他们
to properly protect themselves. They will be stopped.
我们要尽一切可能阻止他们
We will do everything  in our power to stop them.
我说到做到
You have my word on this.
谢谢 市长先生
Thank you, Mr. Mayor.
- 你吃错什么药了 - 干嘛
- What got into you? - What?
我向公众保证
I want to assure the public
我们会尽一切可能逮捕这个犯人
that we are doing everything possible  in our power to apprehend this subject.
凶杀科警探正加班加点
Homicide detectives are working around clock.
分区警员也在同为流浪汉提供帮助的机构沟通
District officers are in contact with  the agencies that work with the homeless.
我不能公开调查的细节
I cannot go into specifics of the investigation
但在此前提下 我可以接受提问
but, with that caveat,  I will take questions.
局长 这些凶案与去年的空屋案
Commissioner, is there any connection  between these murders and those
- 有联系吗 - 没有
- in the vacant homes last year? - No connection.
局长
Commissioner
你会请求FBI介入调查吗
are you asking the FBI to join in the investigation?
副局长Daniels会详细说明
I think deputy commissioner Daniels  is in a position to elaborate on that.
我们接受任何帮助
We'll take whatever help is offered.
当然我们的警探会与Quantico的 行为分析小组密切配合...
certainly Our detectives will work closely with the behavioral analysis unit at Quantico...
副局长 即便以你目前能动用的资源
Deputy, even with all  the resources at your disposal,
抓捕一名连环杀手不是依然很困难吗
isn't it extremely difficult  to catch a serial killer?
我们拥有仅在几年前还达不到的 保存遗传物质的能力
Our ability to secure genetic material and the growing DNA data bank
和高速增长的DNA数据库
are assets unavailable to us even a few years ago.
我们高效利用自身资源的能力
and Our ability to effectively use resources
也随着精密的电脑软件的使用大为增强
has been increased with the aid of sophisticated computer software.
我们还有一些国内最好的 犯罪调查人员全天候工作
And we have some of the best criminal investigators in the nation working 24/7.
正如市长刚刚声明的
As the mayor made very clear a moment ago
现在这是警局的首要任务
this is now a priority for the department.
有在现场发现什么线索吗
Has a note been found at any of the scenes?
此刻我无权透露调查细节
I'm not at liberty to go into any details of the investigation at this time.
要我待着吗
You want me to hang?
他告诉你我是谁了吧
He told you who I am, right?
孩子 谋杀这档事
Son, the thing about murder
永远不会善罢甘休
is it never goes off the books.
我是说 我们会一周一周 一月一月 一年一年地查下去
I mean, we work on 'em for weeks, months, years.
我们坚持不懈 直到有人觉得受够了
We keep on with it until finally someone decides they've had enough,
直到我们从正确的人那儿获得正确的消息
until we get the right word from the right person.
你知道那之后会怎么样吗
And you know what happens then?
当一个案子尘埃落定...
When a case does go down...
那些沉默的人
all those people who kept quiet about it
撒谎的人
who lied about it
那些认为报应不到他身上的人
all of them who thought it wasn't coming back on 'em,
都会背上罪名 并为此服刑
they end up catchin' a charge. And they get time behind that.
服刑?
Time?
你要让我服刑?
You gonna give me time?
如果你对Lex被杀一事知道些什么
If you know something about that boy Lex getting shot
这是你最后一次开口的机会了
now is your last chance to speak to that.
- 你去年给过一份口供... - 你干嘛不允诺把我从这弄出去
- You gave a statement last year... - Why don't you promise to get me outta here?
你们都这么干 不是吗
That's what y'all do, ain't it?
欺骗愚蠢的黑鬼
Lie to dumbass niggers?
在我给这警察一顿老拳前 别让我再看见他
Yo, y'all need to get this police  out my face before I bank his ass.
你是个天才 孩子
You're a natural, kiddo.
你把媒体玩弄于股掌之上
You had them eating out of your hand.
靠 我只是跟着市长的话风走
Shit, I was just following  the mayor's lead.
他想要个满场的新闻发布会
He wants a full-court press, right?
我们可以增加一两个警探
We can add a detective or two.
你可以让巡逻队集中巡逻流浪汉聚居地
And you can ask patrol to concentrate  on posts where vagrants congregate.
但除此之外 副局长 我们无能为力
But other than that, deputy,  the cupboard is bare.
- 但Carcetti说...  - 别误会
- But Carcetti...  - Make no mistake.
他是想让我们解决案子
He wants us to solve the murders.
只是他不想花钱
He just doesn't want it to cost.
别那么惊讶
Don't look so shocked.
你现在也是上层人物了
You're runnin' with the big dogs now.
我们搞清了凶手的手机还不够么
Isn't it enough that we're up  on the killer's cellphone?
你们就不能追踪他的GPS芯片?
Couldn't you track him  on the GPS chip?
他在用即弃手机
He's using a burner
还有我们怀疑他打完电话会把电池取出来
and we suspect he's taking  out the battery between calls.
也没什么能阻止他换电话
And there's nothing to stop him  from changing phones,
用个新号码给记者打电话
calling the reporter from a new number.
所以你们还想录下记者的电话
So you want to tap the reporter's phone  as well.
我们当然要监控电话两头
It stands to reason that we should  monitor this thing from both ends.
我们通常都这么干
It's what we would normally do.
这没什么通常不通常的
Nothing about this is normal.
一个巴尔的摩太阳报记者的电话有问题
A Baltimore Sun reporter's phone  is problematic.
我们得在调查需要
We need to strike a balance
和第一修正案赋予太阳报及其线人的权利间
between your needs as investigators
保持平衡
and the First Amendment rights  of the Sun and its sources.
第一修正案并未保障隐私 法官阁下
The First Amendment does not  guarantee privacy, your Honor.
有案例清楚地表明...
Legal precedent clearly indicates...
听着 我不是说我们不能监听
Look I'm not saying that we can't,
- 但...  - 但什么
- but...  - But what?
但直到我们确认
Until we get the sense
你的疑犯换用手机
that your suspect is changing phones,
我不倾向于批准
I'm not inclined to look with favor
监听巴尔的摩太阳报的电话通讯
on tapping the Baltimore Sun's  telecommunications.
还怕惹火他们?
We're afraid to piss them off?
永远不要和握笔杆子的起争执
Never pick a fight with anyone  who buys ink by the barrel-full.
- 老天  - 那好吧 法官
- Christ.  - Very well, judge.
你要树多少敌啊
How many enemies do you need?
副局长
Deputy.
哪儿弄来的
Where did you get all this?
亲爱的 你不会想知道的
Darling, you do not want to know.
你怎么了
What's up with you?
22单都摆出来了?
Got all 22 out of the drawer?
一次查那么多
Workin' the whole mess at once.
我想重新过一遍
I'm trying to see 'em fresh.
25了 我的三尸案
25. My triple.
查到了Marlo和他手下身上
It comes back to Marlo and his people.
确定?
For sure?
一个优秀的线人告诉我的
A good informant tells me so.
说我其中一个受害人说Stanfield先生的坏话 他报复了
Says one of my vics was talking bad  about Mr. Stanfield, who took it personal.
杀了他 他女人和打手
Killed him, his girl, his muscle.
放了孩子一条生路 我想他还不算太坏
Left the little kids alive,  so I guess he ain't all bad.
外面的人都怕了这混球
People out there so scared  of this motherfucker,
我找不到任何目击证人
I can't get close to an eyewitness  on any of it.
你其他案子进展如何了
Where you at with the rest  of these cases?
有14具尸体还没检验过呢
We don't even have lab work  on 14 of these bodies?
一年了 我还是不停给Landsman写申请
A year later I'm still walking  in written requests into Landsman,
他就把申请塞进抽屉
who just files them away in his drawer.
要是McNulty就会给记者打电话
McNulty would've called a news reporter.
我可不是他
I am not him.
那Bunk会怎么做
Well, what would the Bunk do?
接受被拒绝吗
Take no for a fucking answer?
我们预算被削减了 你知道的
We had cutbacks, you know that.
我们走了三四个测试员
We lost three or four trace examiners.
少了半数的文书
Lost half our clerical.
冰箱坏了 损失了四个月的血样
The freezer went bad,  we lost four months of blood samples.
你们知道吗
Did you know that?
四个月的证物啊 他们还不给我换个冰箱
Four months of evidence and they  still haven't replaced my damn icebox.
我也替你不爽啊
My heart pumps purple piss for you.
现在我手头上是巴尔的摩历史上 最大规模的谋杀案
Now, I got the worst mass murder  in B-more history
你却不能在一年内完成鉴证工作? 拜托 Ron...
and you can't get the trace work back  to me inside of a year? C'mon, Ron...
听着...
Look...
你不能向媒体曝光
You can't go to the press.
我是说 事情传出去有人就要遭殃了
I mean, heads will roll  if this gets out.
这不是谁的错
It isn't anyone's fault.
事实上 某种程度上这还得怪你
In fact, it's a little bit on you,  in a way.
你他妈说什么
The fuck you say?
Annette退休后
After Annette took retirement,
文书工作就难做了
the casework got backed up  worse than ever, right?
我们申请来个人填补实验室助手的空缺
Well, we put in  to fill the lab assistant slot,
但由于预算裁减 他们只能给我们找个临时工
but with the cutbacks, the best  they could give us was a temp.
临时工?
A temp?
对 不用医疗保险 退休金
Yeah. No medical. No pension.
雇个临时工让我们挨过去
A temp hire to get us over for a while.
来吧 给你们看点东西...
Look, I'll show you something...
我们让她整理和归类人体证物...
She was assigned to sort and file  the individual trace elements...
头发 纤维...
Hair, fiber mostly...
你知道 14个犯罪现场的证据
You know, from each of the 14 scenes.
那有什么问题
So what's the problem?
在最开始的案件里
In the initial paperwork,
你写了大约22个案件编号 对吧
you wrote out all 22 CC numbers, right?
- 对  - 但在补充要求里
- Right.  - But in the supplemental requests,
你把所有事件都写在第一个编号下
you put all the incidents  under the initial CC
接着你写了
and then you wrote,
- "等" 记得吗 - 所以呢
- "et al," remember? - So?
她搞不清楚"等"是指什么
She didn't know what "et al" meant.
所以她把所有东西都弄到一个案件编号下了
And she sorted everything  under the single complaint number.
- 你他妈不会是说... - 对
- You don't fuckin' mean... - Yeah.
我们不知道这些分别从哪个犯罪现场来的
We have no idea which one of your scenes  any of this shit came from.
毫无头绪
We don't have a clue.
事实上 除此之外她还是个不错的员工
Actually, except for this she's  been a pretty good employee.
- 监视小组  - 两个 轮当12小时班
- Surveillance teams.  - Two each on 12-hour shifts.
我要他们监控某些跟案子有关的地方
I need them to set up on certain  locations common to our cases.
拜托 Jay 市长也说了 这案子要优先处理
C'mon, Jay. You heard the mayor.  This case is a red ball.
那是 你需要的话Greggs听你调遣
That it is. You can have Greggs,  if you want.
上次我让她帮你 你还把她赶回自己的案子
The last time I offered her up,  you kicked her back to her own casework.
再要别人 就没有了
Other than a second detective,  you are on your own.
这么说都是屁话
So it's all bullshit.
不知道 我觉得市长的演讲还挺不错的
I dunno. I thought the mayor  gave a very nice speech.
比如我就被打动了
I, for one, was moved. Much like the bull  to which you just referred.
- 我跟你说...  - 什么
- Tell you one thing...  - What's that?
跟那边搭上关系的人 就是干掉Joe的人
Motherfucker whose got the connect,  he the one that did Joe.
显而易见
Oh, no doubt.
你们都知道合作社有人被干掉了 Joe Hungry Man
Y'all know the co-op took some hits. Joe.  Hungry Man.
好人啊 尤其是Joe
Good people, especially Joe.
杀他们的人实在是太冷血了
Their passin' was for real, cold blooded.
我知道你们在想什么
I know what you thinkin',
我就坦白说吧...
so I'm a put it out there...
是我的责任
I'm responsible.
大约一周前 经Joe同意 我向Omar下手了
A week or so back, I made a move on Omar,  with Joe's approval.
那基佬没胆子向我报复
The faggot ain't had heart enough  to come at me,
于是他就对跟我亲近的人下手
so he come at those close to me.
现在我要把奖金加倍...
Now I'm doublin' the bounty...
10万块悬赏那基佬的行踪
Hundred large for a whiff  of that dicksuck.
25万要他的人头
Two hundred fifty for his head.
跟那边的联系怎么办
What about the connect?
我搞定了
I got that covered.
基于此 我愿执掌会议
And in light of that fact, I'm a take it  upon myself to conduct this meet.
Slim 我要你接手Hungry Man的收益
Slim, I want you take over  Hungry Man's slice of the cake.
无意冒犯
Meanin' no disrespect,
不过我不是当老大的料
but I ain't cut out to be no CEO.
- 那就Cheese吧  - 没问题 伙计
- Cheese, then.  - No problem, man.
交给我吧
Got you covered.
在我们搞定Omar前
Until we settle up with Omar,
我认为最好暂停此类会议
I think it's best we suspend these meets.
事实上 我不是个喜欢开会的人
In fact, I ain't really one  for meets no how.
各位有什么问题
Anybody got a problem here on out,
就找我 或者先放放
bring it to me, or sit on that shit.
西区有谁需要补货的
Those of you on the Westside  who need to re-up,
就跟我伙计Monk说
holler at my man Monk.
他负责那边的供货
He gonna handle supply over there.
东区就找Cheese
On the Eastside, Cheese.
还有
One more thing.
货价上涨了
Price of the brick going up.
多加三十
Thirty more.
行了 就这么着吧
All right. Enough of this shit.
干嘛
What?
学校的事明年再说
Next year for the schools.
从现在到十二月 我们都盯着流浪汉的事
From now until December, we're all  about the plight of the homeless.
伟大的Whiting发话了
The great whiting has spoken.
我半小时前跟Klebanow申诉来着 但他不答应 抱歉
I appealed to Klebanow half hour ago  but he gave me the thumbs down. I'm sorry.
各位看啊
Check it out, people.
我们的都市主编上全国性节目了
Our Metro desk has some national profile.
我们正谨慎地与调查员展开多方合作
We're being careful to cooperate  with the investigators in every way.
我们报纸并不想在警察和嫌犯间横插一杠子
My newspaper has no desire to get  between the police and the suspect.
但你始终不能否认 这是每个新闻工作者梦寐以求的一刻
But still, wouldn't you agree it's an  incredible moment for any journalist
与山姆之子这样的纯粹的邪恶面对面 (著名连环杀手)
to come face to face with that type  of pure evil like the son of Sam.
这也让你成为了巴尔的摩的Jimmy Breslin (纽约日报记者 山姆之子曾给他写信)
That makes you the Jimmy Breslin  of Baltimore.
不 我不这么认为 我是说...
Well, no, I wouldn't say that.  I mean...
但知道你与凶手取得联系后
But knowing you have been in contact  with a killer,
你是否就只想着来自街头的报道了呢
are you at all concerned about continuing  to report from the street?
不 不是的
No, not at all.
我是说 这是我们的工作
I mean, this is what we do.
作为一个记者 你某种程度上希望处于危险之中
As a reporter, you expect to be  in harm's way at some points.
这是我们的工作
It's what we do.
同意 这是我们的工作
Agreed. It's what we do.
但记者极少
But very rarely does a reporter
会在故事中出现
end up being in the middle of a story -
一个未完待续的故事
an ongoing story -
事关一个
about a murderer
仍逍遥法外的凶手 让自己暴露于
who is still at large and posing a severe
死亡的威胁之中...
and deadly risk to the...
你真该听听早上Phelan怎么说的
You shoulda heard Phelan this morning.
不敢监听报社的电话 他们会找他麻烦
Too scared to tap the newspaper phones  they might shit on him for it.
去他的政客法官
Fuckin' hack judge.
你要那么多监听线干嘛 我们有的足够了
What would you want with more wires?  We got all we need.
我不是想多要监听线 这事关原则...
I don't want another wire.  It's the principle of the thing...
只是听他说话让我火大
It just pissed me off listening to him.
不给监视车
Oh yeah, no surveillance cars.
除了我和Greggs没别人了
They won't go beyond me and Greggs.
从现在开始 就指你和Sydnor尽力而为了
You and Sydnor will have to work it  as best you can for right now.
混蛋
Assholes.
他们得再死一个才行 是吧
They need another body, don't they?
我给我们南区的伙计打个电话
I'll call our man in the Southern.
这样就行了 你们走吧
I can take it from here. Y'all can bounce.
好的 老大
All right, boss.
怎么样啊 Rick?
What up, Rick?
我们又回到老时光了
Just like ol' times for me and you.
你想要什么随便拿 行吗
Whatever you want it's yours, all right?
今晚我只是吓吓你...
Tonight, I'm just gonna take yo' jump...
再给你留点东西
And leave you with a little something.
- 什么 - 带句话
- What's that? - My word in your ear.
Marlo这个贱人
I'm callin' Marlo a straight bitch.
你告诉他杀个瞎子算不了什么
I'm sayin' it don't take much  to shoot down a blind man.
跟他说他就没胆子
And as for him steppin' to me,
冲着我来
you tell that dude he ain't got the heart.
好
All right.
你告诉他 我在街头等着
You tell that man  I'm in the street, waiting.
像个小贱货 藏头露尾的
Just like a little bitch,  he ain't nowhere to be found.
我会告诉他的 我会的
I'll tell him. I will.
捡起你的钥匙 进去
Pick up your keys and go on inside, yo.
你杀了Joe?
You kill Joe?
Hungry?
我也觉得不是
Didn't think so.
现在怎么样
What now?
要搞定这案子还有别的办法
There's more than one way  to skin a case.
已经查过他们的前科了吧
Already ran them for priors, right?
是查过了
Priors, yeah.
但我要把名字在整个数据库里再搜一遍
But I'm gonna run every name you guys  developed through the entire database.
不只是前科 而是所有数据
Not just for priors, but for anything  at all in the miles system.
出庭记录 假释 缓刑
Court appearances, parole, probation,
持枪许可 劳教 保释
gun permits, DOC, open bails.
你这是病急乱投医
You're playing long shots, huh?
亲爱的 我可是老手了
Darlin', I'm playin' the hand  I've been dealt.
一份H档案?
An H-file?
谁办的案子
Who caught the case?
Worden 另一班的
Worden. Other shift.
是继父干的 殴打致死
Stepfather. Beaten to death.
他们走访了母亲 但家里没其他人了
They interviewed the mother,  but no one else in the household.
跟其他人情况不太一样不是吗
Doesn't exactly fit with the others,  does it?
后巷里一顿海扁不是 Marlo Stanfield的风格
A straight up ass-whoopin' in an alley  doesn't seem like Marlo Stanfield.
对 不是
No, it doesn't.
但你还是要查一查
But you're gonna work it anyway.
我礼拜的Pentecostal教堂
In the Pentecostal church  where I was given religion,
会说你昨天是灵魂附体了
it would have been said the spirit  was on you yesterday.
- 也就是灵光乍现  - 赞美上帝
- It got good to me.  - Let praises be.
我有那么多事要处理时 居然有个傻逼开始杀流浪汉
It pissed me off that on top of everything  else I gotta deal with,
着实让我火大
some nutjob starts killing homeless guys.
去他娘的 还有多少破事啊
Fuck already, how many shitbowls are there?
不过他是对的 你表现得太出色了
He's right though. You were great.
要的就是那种激情
That passion was just the thing.
- 你们觉得...  - 我们放弃这个问题
- You think...  - We step out on this issue,
就会给一些全国性的媒体...
it could provide some national presence...
州长去年不是废掉了急救和住房计划吗
Didn't the governor scrap the emergency medical  and housing program last year?
TEMHA:全称过渡期急救医疗和住房援助计划
- 什么来着 TEMHA? - 是的
- What was it, TEMHA? - Yap.
取而代之的是TDAP(临时残疾援助计划)
Replaced it with T-Dap,
削减了对不符合联邦援助条件的对象的资助
which cuts funding to anyone  who doesn't qualify for federal support.
比那还遭 他不接受新的申请 有资格的人也拿不到钱
It's worse than that: He froze eligibility  by disallowing new applications,
计划是把所有人都赶到街头了
which put all kinda folks out on the street.
那我们就抨击共和党人不平等对待穷人
So we slam the Republican  for sticking it to the poor.
行得通的
It plays.
从全国范围来说 你是继承被遗忘的事业...
Nationally, you're taking up the cause  of the forgotten...
再说也没人喜欢流浪汉...
And no one is ever in favor  of homelessness...
对州里而言 你是在对抗撕毁了保险网络的家伙
Statewide, you're going up against the fella  who tore up the safety net.
无家可归者啊
Homelessness.
我会下地狱的
I'll be damned.
基地呼叫2306
Base to 2306.
说吧 Lester
Go ahead, Lester.
你见到有人用手机了吗
You see anybody using a cellphone?
等等
Wait one.
没有
Negative.
等等 有人来了
Hold on. Somebody's here.
Lester?
真不习惯现在这地方萧条的样子
Can't get used to how empty  this place feels nowadays.
那是 不过你会吃惊的发现 没人看着你时工作效率有多高
True, but you'd be surprised  what you can get done when no one's looking.
你得把这些送出去 快到期了
You'll need to serve these.  Running out of time.
这就办
I'll get right on it.
还有些事情我们要收个尾
There's a couple of loose ends  we should cover as well.
- 现在?  - 不是现在 还能什么时候
- Now?  - If not now, when?
庭审日期很快就下来了
The trial date is coming up on us fast.
是啊 但...
Right. But it's...
是因为我说了什么吗
Is it something I said?
不是...
No...
Sydnor正要带过来一个线人
Sydnor is bringing in a CI.
- 如果你在这... - 该死
- And if you're here... - Oh, shit.
抱歉 我...
I'm sorry. I'll ...
...把单子放在这 行吗
...leave you my list, OK?
没问题 我们马上去办
No problem. We'll get right on it.
抱歉 Lester
I'm sorry, Lester,
如果打扰到你
if I was intruding.
不知者无罪
You couldn't know.
你来这干嘛
So why you here?
如果要问Michael和他干的事
If this about Michael and what he into,
你们该知道他不住这儿了
y'all should know he don't live here  no more.
事实上 我是来问你男人的案子的
Actually, I'm following up  on your man's case.
是伐是你跟Worden警探说过了
You spoke to Detective Worden  when it happened.
他是你男朋友 对吧
He was your boyfriend, right?
他不在监狱时...
When he weren't in jail...
还是我最小的小孩的老爸
Father to my youngest.
你知道他是怎么死的
But you know how he died.
被活活打死的
Beaten bad.
按我们的说法 激情犯罪
Crime of passion, as we say.
他才回来没多久
Didn't seem like he was home long enough
应该不会把人惹到这份上
to get somebody that riled at him.
除非跟你有关
Unless, of course, it was over you.
你是说我知道些什么吗
You sayin' I know somethin' about that?
女士 我们有话直说吧
Lady, let's put our cards on the table.
我干这行当也不是一天两天了
I been in this game longer  than a little bit,
有一点我很清楚
and there's one thing I know.
一次像这样的谋杀  常有一个女人主要牵涉其中
A murder like this, there's a woman  at the center of it.
我什么都不知道
I don't know nothin'.
我深知你一清二楚
You know my gut tells me that you do.
我跟你说...
And I'll tell you what...
我们去一趟市里 你跟大陪审团聊聊
We're gonna take a ride downtown,  let you talk to the grand jury.
你不跟他们坦白 他们就会给你一张提供实质物证证人状
You're not straight with them, they'll  give you a material witness warrant.
然后你就在女子拘留所里待上几周
And you sit over at woman's detention  for a couple of weeks.
那对悲伤阶段疗效显著
It's amazing what it does  for the grieving process.
- 收拾东西吧  - 我哪儿也不去
- Get your things.  - I ain't goin' nowhere.
要么跟我去 要么坐警车
It's me or the wagon.
警探 我发誓 这事跟我无关
Detective, I swear, I ain't in this.
你不该跟我谈
It ain't me you wanna talk to.
跟我孩子说去 他知道
It's the boy, he know.
他跟犯下这事的人混在一起
He runnin' with them who did it.
你是要把我引入歧途
You just tryin' to put me off the scent.
你得相信我
You gotta believe me.
他跟我说Devar不会回家了
He told me Devar wasn't comin' home,
那时我们还不知道他的死讯
'fore we even knowed he was dead.
你说他跟他们混在一起 他们是谁
You said he's runnin' with them?  Runnin' with who?
Chris Snoop 那群帮派分子
Chris, Snoop, all them gangsters.
还有谁在这附近杀人
Who else doin' all the killin' around here?
我看看你的相机
Let me see your camera.
在你的计时器里加入一分钟六张
Add a minute-six to your times.
好的
Got it.
就这个 看
Here it is. Look at this.
响一声 连线 沉默
Single ring. Connection. Silence.
你拍到了什么
What do you have?
拍了这仨
I took these three.
他们就在那儿晃荡
They're just hangin' around.
Monk什么时候离开的
What time did Monk leave?
1点24分 两分钟后
1:24. Two minutes later.
跟Marlo说的什么无关
It's not what Marlo's sayin',
而是他发了什么 你看Monk
it's what he's sendin'. Look at Monk.
嗯 短信
Yeah. Text message.
短信? 我得提醒你 警探
Text? Need I remind you, Detective,
这些小伙可是巴尔的摩社会大学毕业的
these young men are products  of Baltimore City schools.
再说了 看他手机拿得多远
Besides, look how far away  he's holding his phone.
那么远怎么读短信
Too far away to be reading a text.
不 孩子 是图片
Nah, son. Pictures.
图片...
Pictures...
你他妈看什么看
What the fuck you lookin' at?
你知道他们怎么干 对吧
You know what they do, right?
他们取笑你 让你接近目标
They tease you. They let you get close
就在你要解决案子的时候
and just when you're  about to pull the case,
他们就扯你后腿
they rip the fuckin' rug out  from under you.
我没骗人 是有个连环杀手逍遥法外
I'm not lying. We got a fuckin' serial  killer on the loose.
你不知道
You didn't know that?
报纸上都写着呢
It's in the goddamn paper.
我得到什么支援了 就他妈一个警探
What support do I get?  One fuckin' detective.
他们想玩他们简单的游戏 行
They wanna play  their simple-ass games, fine.
但我会做我该做的事
But I gotta do what I gotta do.
不好意思
Excuse me.
Oscar
Yeah, Oscar.
漂亮
Beautiful.
当然 在哪
Absolutely. Where?
这就过去
On my way.
伙计 你不能让事情这样影响你
Man, you can't let it get to you like this.
我们干嘛不去买一堆玩具给你孩子
Why don't we go buy up a bunch of toys and take 'em to your kids?
你听不懂我说话吗 Omar盯上我们了 我怎么能接近我家人
You ain't hearin' me. How can I go near my people with Omar on us?
他怎么会知道他们的存在
How he gonna find out about them?
我们又怎么知道那瞎子的存在的
How we find out about the blind man?
- 滚 - 是Omar! 是Omar!
- Get. - It's Omar! It's Omar!
你也是 矮子
You too, shorty.
Omar! 是Omar!
Omar! It's Omar!
今天的钱晚了点
Money a little late today.
你腿上的枪子儿能让你跟Marlo解释
That buckshot in your leg should help you explain yourself to Marlo.
至于另外那两个 他们会希望我给他们两枪
As for them other two they gonna wish that I'd peppered them a bit.
你告诉Marlo我烧了他的钱
Now you make sure you tell old Marlo I burned the money.
因为我不稀罕那些纸
'Cause it ain't about that paper.
我是要伤他的人 搅乱他的世界
It's about me hurtin' his people, messin' with his world.
告诉他他不够男人跟Omar面对面
Tell that boy he ain't man enough to come down to the street with Omar.
告诉他!
You tell him that!
我的警司和两个搭档到得比我早
My sergeant and two side partners got here before me.
接着值班指挥官也到了 现在值班警官也在路上了
Then the shift commander showed. Now the duty officer is on his way.
就为一个抵达前死亡?
For a DOA?
你和Lester在这搞出的事
Well, you and Lester started some shit here, son.
现在一个抵达前死亡的报告 会一下子把所有人都招来
Now a DOA call brings everyone in a heartbeat.
上帝保佑
God bless.
- 图片? - 手机里的图片
- Pictures? - Photographs on cellphones.
那就需要新的电脑捕捉图片
Now that means new PC to capture the photos
还需要新的设备
and new equipment that could do it.
我怎么把这个写进我那 狗屁流浪汉杀手的作案模式里
How do I write that into my bullshit homeless killer's MO?
我们刚开始时 你说我们只需要些窃听器
When we started this, you said all we needed were some bugs,
一两个相机 一两周内我们就会有 这是你说的
a camera or two, and in a couple of weeks, we'd have them. That's what you said.
所以我搞大动静来给你买单
So I cranked up my bullshit to pay for that
但你又要监听线
but no, then you needed a wiretap.
所以我再接再厉 给你搞来了监听线
So I went along, I got you the wiretap.
接着你又要监视小组
Then you ask for surveillance teams,
我这边还没着落呢 你又跟我要这个 搞什么飞机
but before I can get to that, you came to me with this. I mean, what the fuck?
我得说 Lester 我不想伤害你的感情
I gotta tell you, Lester, I don't want to hurt your feelings,
但我知道为什么每次你张口Daniels都不安了
but I can see why Daniels cringed every time you opened your fucking mouth.
你就是领导的噩梦啊
You're a supervisor's nightmare.
我只是跟着线索走
I'm just following the thread.
假设我们能拦截到图片 这样就能抓到Marlo吗
Say we get you the intercept on your pictures, will that give us Marlo?
很可能图片是加密的
It'll be coded, probably,
但我相信我们能破解
but I'm sure we can break it.
那就会让我们知道他们是怎么交易的 通常那就足够了
That'll tell us how they do business, and usually, that's enough.
但也未必
Or not.
事实上 我让Sydnor乔装打扮
But the truth is, I'm running Sydnor ragged
在那附近转悠 监视电话出入
just staying on a couple of mopes and monitoring calls.
等到我们破解他们的密码
Now, when we're up on their code,
我们就需要更多人手 捣毁他们的藏毒点和补货点
we're gonna need more manpower to run down a stash or a re-up.
- 这么多事我们做不来 - 我也没法再瞒天过海了
- We can't do it all. - I can't juke this thing any more than I have.
昨晚 半个警局的人在我之前
Last night, half the police department turned up
赶到Oscar的案发现场
at Oscar's crime scene before I could get there.
我们没法再制造一起谋杀了
We can't make another murder.
谢谢你的牛奶
Thanks for the milk.
甜甜圈没牛奶怎么行
What's a donut without milk?
你刚说到你的第二次服役..
So you were talking about your second tour...
- 糟糕的那次 - 对
- The bad one. - Yeah.
第二次服役把我弄得很惨 但他们根本不想听
Second tour fucked me up good. But they don't wanna hear it.
谁不听
Who doesn't?
通常是司令部和高级军官
Mostly, it's command and the senior EMS.
他们放言海军陆战队不会患创后精神障碍 但他们一样会
They put it down that marines don't get P.T.S.D. But they do.
能告诉我发生了什么事吗
Can you tell me what happened?
Terry 你能说说吗
Terry, can you talk about it?
我们第二次服役还有一个月
We had a month left on the tour,
在费卢杰外执行一项扫荡任务
working an S-and-A mission outside Fallujah.
我是副领队
I was assistant team leader.
我们的M998都上了装甲
Our M-niner-niner-eights were retrofitted with up-armor kits.
M998?
M-niner-niner-eight?
悍马 抱歉
A humvee, sorry.
他们命名的号码很大
They're big on nomenclature.
总之我们完成了扫荡 正在回去的路上
Anyway we finished our sweep, headed back in, right?
本来一切正常 接着 砰...
It was all good. Then, bam...
我们的领行车遭遇抬高的路边弹
Our lead vehicle was hit with an elevated I.E.D.
爆炸把M50枪手撕成了两半
The blast tore the M-fifty gunner in half.
把悍马像个火柴盒般抛起
Flipped the humvee like a matchbox car.
司机失去了两只手
Driver lost both his hands.
鲜血四溅 他还他妈的在笑
Blood shooting out all over. He's fuckin' laughin'.
一遍遍地说 "看 妈 手没了"
Saying over and over, "Look, Ma, no hands."
那是我忘不了的笑声
It's the laughing I can't shake.
真诡异
Weird.
因为他没事 知道吗 我是说 他现在比我好
'Cause he's OK, you know? I mean, he's better than me.
给自己安了对假肢 每个八万
Got himself a couple of prosthetic mitts, eighty thousand apiece.
然后怎样了
What happened next?
没什么 我们冲了出去 守住了
Nothing really. We pushed out, secured the perimeter.
军医尽了力 我们等到了空运撤离
Corpsman did what he could, an' we waited for the casevac.
我不是要抹黑谁的作品
I'm not looking to shit on another guy's copy,
我只想让你知道有这么回事
I just wanted you to know this was out there.
我参加了个Bel Air-Edison的社区会议
I'm at a community meeting in Bel Air-Edison
听一些校区的事 听到有个女人不停唠叨这些
to hear about school zoning and this woman talked my ear off about this.
她说孩子们一毛钱都没见着
She said the kids never saw a dime.
我是说 我希望她是放屁
I mean, I'm hoping this is all bullshit.
- Scott 怎么样 - 很好 你看了图片了吗
- Hey, Scott. How's it coming? - Pretty good. You seen the art?
嗯 不错 听着
Yeah. Good stuff. Listen,
我听到关于你几周前写的一个新闻的投诉
got a complaint about a story you wrote a couple weeks ago.
- 死于海鲜过敏的女人那个 记得吗 - 那个怎么了
- The woman who died from an allergic reaction to seafood. Remember? - What about it?
认识死者姐妹的一个女人说 我们的新闻为那些孩子筹了不少钱
Lady knows the dead woman sister says our story made a lot of money for those kids.
- 我们详述了一个奖学金 - 所以呢
- A scholarship fund we wrote up. - So?
她说她姐姐有欺诈的历史 还被定过罪
She says the sister has a history of fraud, convictions on it.
她说那些钱都跑到大西洋城赌场去了
She says all the money went to Atlantic City casinos
- 孩子们一毛钱也没见到 - 老天 搞什么...
- and kids never saw a dime. - Christ, who the fuck...
我知道 可能是一些三姑六婆胡侃
I know. It's probably some old biddy talkin' about stuff she don't know,
但也许你该回去再跟那家人对对
but maybe you should go back and check with the family,
看我们用不用为此负责
see if we don't get took on this, huh?
不 不 不用现在 等你归好档 打几个电话就行
No, no. Not now. After you file. Just make a couple calls, huh?
- 这是绑架 - 事实上 我不确定
- This is kidnapping. - Actually, I'm not sure.
我问他要不要去某处吃个饭聊个天 就能赚个100块
I asked him if he wanted $100 to go someplace for dinner and talk
- 他就走向了我的车 - 你给了他一百块?
- and he walked to my car. - You give him the hundred?
塞到他夹克里了
Stuffed it in his jacket.
他没事 Lester 他很好
He's fine, Lester. He's great.
- 你觉得他能找到回家的路吗 - 总能找到的
- Think he'll find his way back home? - Eventually.
到那时 我们就搞定Marlo了 我们就结束这一切了
By then, we'll be done with Marlo, we'll have shut this thing down.
至于这家伙发生的事...
As far as what happened to this guy...
他们会写成是互助会的恶作剧
They'll write it off as some fraternity prank.
- 他知道我们是警察吗 - 不知道
- Does he know we're cops? - No.
就算他能猜出来 谁会相信他 他傻的
Even if he figures it out, who's gonna believe him? He's nuts.
- 你怎么知道他傻 - 首先 你看他
- How do you know he's nuts? - First of all, just look at him.
他一直在撞墙 其次... 我拿了他的处方
He's fucking bouncing off the walls. Second of all... I got his scrip.
我给大学急诊室打了电话 是抗精神病药
I called the university ER. It's an anti-psychotic.
于是...
So...
我拿了他的身份证
I took his I.D.,
我会把他的名字从处方上除掉 把这个留给他...
I'll scratch his name off the scrip and leave him with this...
这是我从Oscar给我们的 第一个流浪汉死者身上弄到的
I got that one from the first homeless death Oscar gave us.
那个尸僵太严重的 Donald什么的
The one that was too rigored. Donald somebody or other.
原籍克利夫兰 俄亥俄庇护所
It had him in a Cleveland, Ohio shelter.
McNulty 你真该被拿去做心理学研究
McNulty, you are deserving of serious psychological study.
你要电脑拦截手机图片 这就是了
You need PC to intercept cellphone photos. Well here it is, right here.
我们把这家伙帮上彩带
We send photos of this guy
的照片用电池将尽的手机 发给那个傻逼记者
all ribboned up from a dry cellphone to that goofy reporter,
附上一条对他的报道发牢骚的信息
along with a message bitching about his stories.
"我不是变态"之类的 现在 杀手说
"I ain't no pervert," or whatever. Now, the killer says,
你们再也找不到尸体 只有受害人消失前...
you ain't gonna find no more bodies. Only photos of the victims...
的照片
Before they disappear.
看看这个可怜的家伙 不敢相信我们要这么做
Look at this poor sucker. I don't believe we're gonna do this.
他一消失 整个城市都会陷入疯狂 你拿到你的图片拦截装置
He disappears, the city goes batshit. You get your photo intercepts,
我们要捣毁Marlo的补货点时
and when we need to run down one of Marlo's re-ups,
你要的人也有了
you got all the manpower you need.
- 然后Marlo也完蛋了 - 狠狠地完蛋了
- And Marlo falls. - Falls hard.
别告诉我你把这个的标签也搞错了
Don't fucking tell me you mislabeled this, too.
我要比对已知嫌疑人
I want comparisons between known suspects
和这个犯罪现场的DNA
and the DNA from this scene.
看这个死样 估计采了一大把DNA吧
By the looks of it, we got a whole lot of DNA outta this mess.
- 马上 混蛋 马上 - 首要任务
- Now, motherfucker. Right now. - Top of my list.
等我们完成流浪汉谋杀案的调查后就给你弄
As soon as we work through all the trace from the homeless killings.
那是首要任务 Bunk
That's the priority, Bunk.
- 流浪汉谋杀案 - 所以资源都要为此服务 抱歉
- The homeless killings. - Everything is backed up behind that, sorry.
你哥们McNulty现在正是炙手可热啊
Your boy McNulty has everyone's attention right now.
是Larry吧
So it's Larry, huh?
好吧 Larry 你跟好人在一起 一切都会很棒的
OK, Larry. You're with good people here. It's all gonna be great.
你会喜欢这地方 暖和 还有舒服的床
You're gonna like this place. It's warm, they got nice beds.
最好的是 我给你现金让你走进去
And best of all, I gave you cash money just for walking in the door.
来吧 Larry
Come on, Larry.
会好的 我保证
It's gonna be fine. I promise.
你想亲自上阵审理Clay?
You feel up for trying Clay yourself?
我是说 离你上次亲自出马 审理罪案有段时间了
I mean, it's been a while since you tried a criminal case personally.
我想发了一份声明
It sends a statement, I think.
我们该从证人名单开始 看看能不能减少一些
We should start with our witness list. See if we can pare that down any,
因为巴尔的摩的陪审团容易分心
out of respect for the distracted nature of a Baltimore jury.
首先 我还有个别的要交给你
First, there's something else I need to bring up.
- 旧的大陪审团文件? - 密封的诉状
- Old grand jury stuff? - Sealed indictments.
密封的记录 多不胜数
Sealed transcripts. Dozens of them.
在一个被杀的东区毒贩的书桌里搜出来的
Pulled from the desk of a shot-to-death drug dealer in east Baltimore.
副局长拿给我的
The deputy ops brought me those.
我们有人泄密
We have a leak.
他在我工作的地方出现
And he showed up, outside where I work.
思维混乱 我想他是迷路了 就把他带这儿来了
He was confused. Lost I think. So I brought him here.
Donald 你从哪来
Donald, where you from?
跟这位女士说 Donald
Tell the lady, Donald.
巴尔的摩
Baltimore.
但他跟我说他来自克利夫兰
But he told me he came from Cleveland.
Donald 你有身份证吗
Donald, do you have identification?
上面说的是克利夫兰
This does say Cleveland.
Donald 不如我们给你些吃的吧
Donald, why don't we get you something to eat?
没事的 来
It's OK. Come on.
- 行了吗 - 太棒了 Gus
- We're good to go? - It's great, Gus.
太棒了
It sings.
- 嘿 Scotty - 嘿
- Hey, Scotty boy. - Hey.
好文章 我是说这才像话
Hey. Great piece. I mean this one really feels like the real deal.
- 干得好 - 谢了
- It's great work. - Thanks.
我最欣赏的是你没有写太过分
What I like most about it is that you didn't overwrite it.
没过度润色 没有浮夸的形容词
No extra color. No puffy adjectives.
只有紧凑 陈述式的句子 你是让这位前海军陆战队员在说他的故事
Just tight, declarative sentences. You really let this ex-marine tell his story.
- 谢谢 Gus - 编排编辑先生
- Thanks, Gus. - Hey, Mr. Slot man,
读读 抹一把泪 我说的是字面上的意思
read it and weep. And I mean that literally.
Scott 你为那个投诉打了电话了吗
Oh, Scott. Did you get a chance to drop a couple calls on that complaint?
都是屁话 我跟社区里的人聊过了
It's bullshit. I talked to people in the neighborhood.
那姐姐是好人 但有个非亲非故的女人
Sister's good people, but there's another woman up there, unrelated,
老是因开空头支票什么的事被捕
keeps getting arrested for kiting checks and stuff.
她每次被捕用的都是那个姐妹的名字
She uses the sister's name every time she gets locked up.
她这么干过四五次了 是啊 太疯狂了
She's done it like three or four times now. Yeah, it's crazy.
但她是清白的 大家都这么说
But sister's clean. Everyone says so.
好吧
OK.
我还能为他做点什么吗
Is there anything else I can do for him?
不用了 交给我们吧 谢谢你带他过来
No, we've got it. But thanks for bringing him in.
多数人都会无视他们
Most people, they just ignore them.
我只想弄好你的档案
I just want to get your paperwork taken care of.